☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[LOUD THRUMMING]
[BOTH] The gate.
入口
I don't understand. You've seen this before?
我不明白  你之前见过这玩意吗
- Not exactly. - Then what, exactly?
-算不上见过  -那到底是什么
- All you need to know is it's bad. - [STEVE] It's really bad.
-你只需要知道这很糟糕  -非常糟糕
Like, end-of-the-human-race-as-we-know-it kind of bad.
和人类灭绝一样糟糕
And you know about this how?
你是怎么知道的
Um, Steve? Where's your Russian friend?
史蒂夫  你的苏联朋友去哪了
[ALARM BLARING]
Shit.
糟了
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
Halt! Halt!
站住  站住
Shit.
该死
- Go, go, go, go, go! - [DUSTIN] Shit.
-快跑  快跑  -该死
[STEVE] Move! Let's move!
跑  赶紧跑
[OFFICE CHAIR SQUEAKS]
[STEVE] Go! Shit! Shit, shit, shit!
快跑  糟了糟了
[STEVE] Go, go, go!
快跑  快跑
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[SHRIEKS]
[DUSTIN] Holy shit! Holy shit! Holy shit!
完了  完了  完了
Holy shit! Holy shit! Shit! Holy shit! Holy shit!
[GASPS FOR AIR] Holy shit!
完蛋了
- Guards! Go! - This way!
-守卫来了  快跑  -这边
- [GRUNTING] - [GUARDS YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
- [STEVE] Oh, shit! Oh, shit! - [ERICA] Whoa!
该死  该死
[STEVE GRUNTS]
- Come on! Go, go, go, go, go! - [ROBIN] Come on!
-快跑  跑快点  -快跑
- Shit! - [ROBIN] This way!
-该死  -走这边
- [ROBIN] Come on, quick! - [STEVE] Hold the door!
-快点  -把门抵住
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
Robin!
罗宾
Shit!
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
该死
- [STEVE] Help me, come on! - [ERICA] Here! Come on, let's go!
-快来帮我  -过来  赶紧跑
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
- Come on! - Go! Just get out of here!
-快跑啊  -快跑  离开这里
Go, come on, now!
来啊  快跑啊
No! Just go get some help, okay?
不  去找人来救我们好吗
[STEVE] What are you doing?!
你在干吗
- [BOTH] Go! - [GUARDS YELLING]
快跑
I won't forget you!
我不会抛弃你们的
[BOTH] Go!
跑啊
[ROBIN YELPS, GRUNTS]
[YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[GUNS COCKING]
[FLOURESCENT LIGHTS BUZZING]
[LOW FREQUENCY RUMBLING]
[FLUTTERING SOUND]
He's here.
他在这
[WILL SHIVERS]
[ELEVEN BREATHES DEEPLY]
[SHRIEKING]
- Shit. - Nancy!
-糟了  -南茜
[JONATHAN] Run!
快跑
[NANCY] Damn!
该死
Hey!
[NANCY GRUNTS]
[JONATHAN] Come on!
拜托
- [ROARS] - [NANCY WHIMPERS]
Hey!
Hey, hey, hey! Two at a time!
一次只能进两人
[CREATURE SHRIEKING]
[PANTING]
[SNARLING]
[CREATURE SNARLS, GROWLS]
[NANCY WHIMPERS]
[CREATURE SNARLS]
[SHRIEKING]
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
[PANTING]
[CLANGING]
[JONATHAN GRUNTS]
[SNARLING]
[SQUELCHING SOUND]
Oh, my God.
[INTENSE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
老天爷
Jonathan...
乔纳森
No! Nancy!
不  南茜
Jonathan!
乔纳森
[GRUNTS]
No, no! Nancy!
不  不  南茜
[BEEPING]
Stairs.
走楼梯
Goddamn it!
该死
[BUBBLING AND SQUELCHING]
[SNARLING]
[ROARING]
[PANTING]
[CREATURE SQUELCHES]
[CREATURE SNARLING]
[SNARLING CONTINUES]
[CREATURE GROWLING]
[ROARING]
[SHRIEKING]
- Jesus! - What the f...
-上帝啊  -这什么...
[ROARING]
- [ELEVEN YELLS] - [CREATURE WAILS]
- [ELEVEN YELLS] - [CREATURE GROANS]
- [YELLS] - [CREATURE SHRIEKS]
[YELLS]
- [SNARLS] - [ELEVEN YELLS]
- Go. - Nancy!
-快走  -南茜
Are you okay? Are you okay?
你还好吗
[ALL PANTING]
[LIGHTS BUZZING]
紧急通道
[SQUELCHING]
[EERIE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[BUBBLING AND SQUELCHING]
[RHYTHMIC GRUNTING]
[SQUELCHING SOUND]
[CREATURE GRUNTS]
It's time.
是时候了
[CREATURE SHRIEKS]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
怪奇物语  第三季第六集
第六章
合众为一
["STAND UP AND MEET YOUR BROTHER" PLAYING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
♪ Stand up and meet your brother, honey ♪
♪ One color or another ♪
♪ But he's still ♪
♪ He's still your brother ♪
♪ Reach out and take his hand ♪
♪ I want y'all to ♪
- ♪ Help him understand... ♪ - [GRUMBLES]
Hey! Excuse me.
等一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
等一下  等一下
What... what are you doing? What's... what's this doing here?
你在做什么  这是在干什么
- What? - Your stand.
-怎么了  -你的摊位
It's right in the main thoroughfare.
正好挡在大路中间
Where do you want it, sir?
你想挪到哪呢  先生
[SCOFFS]
Over there with the rest of the goddamn food stalls.
和其它的食品摊一起
It isn't rocket science.
这又不是什么难事
Sheesh, do I have to do everything myself?
是不是所有的活都得我自己干
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[LARRY] My friends in state PD,
我在州警局的朋友们
highway patrol, they're all on the lookout.
还有公路巡逻队  他们都盯着呢
I got eyes everywhere.
我的眼目无处不在
The second he pops up...
他一出现
I get a call.
我就会接到电话
A call?
电话
Yes. A call. [CHUCKLES]
是的  电话
I mean, what more do you people want me to do?
你们还想让我做什么
We want you to find him.
我们想让你找到他
[SUCKS LIPS]
Let me explain something to you.
我跟你解释一下吧
This man is a moron, okay?
这个人就是个白痴  好吗
He's driving around in a yellow convertible, for Christ's sakes.
他开着一辆黄色敞篷车到处转悠  老天
He sticks out like a sore thumb.
他简直就是猪立鸡群
I will find him.
我会找到他的
And, when I do,
而且当我找到他的时候
may I suggest you bring some backup with you this time?
我建议你带些增援来好吗
- Backup. - Some comrades.
-增援  -带些同志
Since last time, he got the better of you.
鉴于上一次他可是让你大败而归
[LARRY GRUNTS]
- [DOOR WHINES SHUT] - [CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [LARRY GROANS] - [HISSING NOISE]
[RIDE POWERS UP]
Please...
求你了
I... I didn't mean that.
我不是这个意思
You... You don't need backup.
你不需要增援
This man is your fault,
这个人是你的错
your problem.
是你惹的麻烦
You're lucky you still breathe.
你该庆幸你还活着
[CHOKING] Very lucky.
非常庆幸
Please.
求你了
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I... I have a bad temper.
我脾气不好
I'm going to therapy.
我会去心理治疗
You have one day to find this man for me.
给你一天时间给我找到这个人
Nod if you understand.
听懂了就点头
[CHOKING]
[PLAYFUL ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[HOPPER] Two Whoppers,
两个特大汉堡
extra ketchup, large fry,
多加番茄酱  大份薯条
pack of Marlboro Reds,
一包红万宝路香烟
and one extra-large...
还有一份超大杯的
Slurpee.
思乐冰
Burger King is nowhere near the 7-Eleven, by the way.
汉堡王比起711便利店的口味差多了
Never said it was.
我又没说过它好
Let's try this again. Joyce.
再来试试吧  乔伊
Alexei,
阿列克西  这些发电机
the generators,
what are they powering?
在给什么供能
And tell him that we know it is not the Starcourt Mall,
还有告诉他  我们知道不是给星庭商场的
so he can stop selling us that crap.
让他别再给我们搪塞些废话
[IN RUSSIAN] Those generators you were working on,
你研究的这些发电机是在给什么东西供能
what are you powering?
We know it's not the mall.
我们知道这不是给商场供电
[IN RUSSIAN] This tastes like shit strawberry.
这是该死的草莓味
- What'd he say? - He says,
-他说什么  -他说
"It's strawberry."
"是草莓"
I'm sorry?
什么
His... Slurpee.
他的思乐冰
[MURRAY] He says it's strawberry.
他说这是草莓味的
So what?
那又怎样
Hop, he did ask for cherry. I mean...
霍普  他之前的确要了樱桃味的
Well, they didn't have cherry.
他们没有樱桃味的
They didn't have it.
他们没有
And it doesn't matter,
而且这根本不重要
because it all tastes the same, okay?
因为尝起来都一样  好吗
It is sugar on ice. You tell him that.
都是糖水加冰  你给他说
Tell him what?
给他说什么
You tell him that it all tastes the goddamn same!
告诉他这尝起都他妈一样
[MURRAY, IN RUSSIAN] It's all the same.
这都一样
Sugar on ice. No difference.
糖水加冰  没区别
[IN RUSSIAN] Tell that stupid man it is not the same in the slightest,
告诉那个傻子  一点都不一样
and I would like the cherry I requested.
还有我要我说的樱桃味
[IN ENGLISH] He respectfully disagrees.
他表示明确不同意
[MURRAY] It's not the same at all,
完全不一样
and he would like...
而且他想
- cherry. - [CHUCKLES]
樱桃味
Oh, yeah? You tell him... he can forget it.
是吗  你告诉他  别想了
[IN RUSSIAN] He says forget it. No cherry.
他说别想了  没有樱桃味
[IN RUSSIAN] No cherry, no deal.
没有樱桃  没有交易
[LAUGHS]
[IN ENGLISH] He says,
他说
"No cherry...
没有樱桃
no deal."
就没有交易
[SMACKS LIPS]
[MURRAY] Yeah.
Hm.
[INHALES SHARPLY]
Mm.
- [HOPPER YELLS] - [MURRAY] Oh, shit!
妈的
- [YELLING] - [JOYCE] No, Hop...
别  霍普
- [GRUNTING] - Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
等等  等等  等等
- I'm not gonna hurt him! - [JOYCE] What are you doing?
-我不会伤害他  -你在干什么
- [HOPPER GROWLS] - Come on! Come on!
别这样  别啊
I'm just giving him an opportunity
我就只是给他个机会
to get his own damn...
让他喝到他自己该死的
cherry Slurpee!
樱桃思乐冰
- [HOPPER GRUNTS] - [ALEXEI WHIMPERS]
[WHIMPERS]
Jim, that man is an enemy of the state.
吉姆  那个人是国家的敌人
Yeah, who's been jerking us around for a full day!
他耍了我们一整天
I get him his cherry Slurpee, then what?
我给他买了他要的樱桃思乐冰  然后呢
He wants a helicopter to charter him to his own private island.
他会要一架直升机把他接到他的私人岛屿上
I have dealt with assholes like this
我这辈子都在应付
my entire life.
这样的混蛋
[HOPPER] Yesterday in the woods, he could've escaped,
昨天在树林里  他本可以跑掉的
- but he didn't. - [CHUCKLES]
但他没有
He stuck with us.
他一直跟着我们
Why do you think that is?
你觉得是为什么
It's because...
是因为
he's scared.
他害怕
[HOPPER] He's scared.
Not of us,
不是因为我们
of them.
是因为他们
He's scared of that seven-foot-tall Russian freak
他怕那些能像我们一样能轻易杀了他的
who could've killed him just as easily as us.
七英尺高的苏联怪胎
Smirnoff knows
司木露知道
that if he runs back to his comrades without a scratch on him,
如果他毫无伤痕地回到战友身边
they're gonna think that he spilled his guts.
他们会觉得他泄密了
So, whether he likes it or not, we...
所以  无论他喜不喜欢
are the best chance he's got.
我们都是他最好的机会
Ooh! [GRUNTS IN PAIN]
I give him 30 seconds before he comes knocking on that door,
我给他30秒来敲门
right back into our arms,
回到我们怀里
with a new sense of humility.
带着新的谦逊
- ["NEUTRON DANCE" PLAYS] - ♪ I don't wanna take it anymore ♪
[LAUGHS GIDDILY]
- Jim... - Uh...
吉姆
I, uh, believe he has started the car.
我觉得他在发动汽车
Hopper.
霍普
You know, testing us. He's just calling my bluff.
你懂得  测试我们  他只是在虚张声势
♪ 'Cause I work so hard to make it every day ♪
♪ Woo-ooh ♪
I believe he is now driving away.
我觉得他正开车走
[GRUMBLES]
[SCOFFS]
[JOYCE GRUMBLES] Jim. Jim, move.
吉姆  吉姆  让开
- Joyce, Joyce... - Move, move, move!
-乔伊  乔伊  -让开  让开  让开
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh, huh ♪
♪ And it's hard to say ♪
♪ Just how some things never change ♪
♪ And it's hard to find ♪
♪ Any strength to draw the line ♪
♪ Ooh, I'm just burning doin' the neutron dance ♪
♪ I'm just burning doin' the neutron dance ♪
[ENGINE SWITCHES OFF]
♪ I know there's a pot of gold for me ♪
♪ All I've got to do is just believe... ♪
[MUTTERING IN RUSSIAN]
♪ Doin' the neutron dance ♪
♪ And I'm just burning... ♪
I'm sorry, what did he say?
不还意思  他刚说什么
He says he likes strawberry, too.
他说他也喜欢草莓味
- ♪ I'm just burning ♪ - ♪ In my feet ♪
♪ Doin' the neutron dance, woo-hoo ♪
[DUSTIN] So, when we set fire to the hub,
所以  当我们向枢纽开火时
we drew the Demodogs away so El could close the gate.
我们把魔狗引开好让一一关上大门
But now, for some insane reason,
不过现在  由于一些疯狂的原因
the Russians appear to be trying to reopen it,
苏联人似乎想重新打开它
which just destroys everything we risked our lives for.
打开这个摧毁了我们冒着生命危险换来的一切
By "we", you're including Lucas?
"我们"包括卢卡斯吗
Yes, of course.
是的当然
So, all that shit you told me, Lucas was there?
所以  你说的这些是  卢卡斯都参与了
- Yeah. - My brother, Lucas Charles Sinclair?
-对  -我哥哥  卢卡斯·查尔斯·辛克莱
Yes!
是的
I don't believe you.
我不信
Wait, so you believe everything about El and the gate
等等  所以关于一一和大门的事你都相信
and the Demodogs and the Mind Flayer,
还有魔狗和吸灵魔
but you question your brother's involvement?
却质疑你哥哥的参与度
That's correct.
正是
Makes total sense.
很有说服力
- Um, you need help with that? - No.
-你需要帮忙吗  -不
- Well, I mean, it's taking a while, so... - Yeah, no shit, Sherlock.
我是说  这得花点时间  所以 当然了  夏洛克
All right, so if we don't find
好吧  如果我们
a more efficient method to stop these fans,
无法找到更有效的办法停下这些风扇
we're never gonna find help,
我们就找不到支援
and your ice cream buddies are screwed.
你的那些冰淇淋好哥们就都完了
Yeah, with that attitude, they are. Jee-zus!
对  就那个态度  肯定完了  老天爷
I'm just being realistic.
我只是很现实
I mean, we've made it about point-three miles in nine hours.
我是说  我们用了九小时才走了三百米
Then we had to walk three hours down that tunnel,
我们还得花三小时走到隧道尽头
so I'd estimate ten miles back to the elevator,
所以我估计回到电梯的十英里
which should take us approximately twelve-and-a-half days.
大概得花上我们十二天半
Did you just do all of that in your head?
你在脑子里算出来的吗
I'm good with numbers.
我擅长算术
Holy shit. You're a nerd.
我靠  你是个书呆
Come again?
再说一次
You... are... a... nerd.
你  是  书  呆
Okay, you better take that back, nerd.
你最好收回那句话  呆子
Can't put the truth back in the box.
真相不能被关回盒子里
- But it's not the truth. - Let's examine the facts, shall we?
-但那根本就不是真相  -我们来检验一下
Fact one: you're a math whiz, apparently.
事实一  很明显  你是个数学奇才
That was a pretty straightforward equation.
那只是个很简单的方程
Fact number two: you're a political junkie.
事实二  你是个政治迷
Just because I don't agree with Communism as an ideology...
就因为我不同意共产主义是一种意识形态
Fact number three: you love My Little Pony.
事实三  你很喜欢小马宝莉
And what does My Little Pony have to do with this?
小马宝莉和这个有什么关系
Ah, let's recall the ponies' latest adventure, shall we?
我们来回忆一下小马最近的探险  好吗
The evil centaur team and Tirek
邪恶的半人马队和泰瑞克提雷克
turns Applejack into a dragon at Midnight Castle,
在午夜城堡把苹果嘉儿变成了一条龙
and then Megan and the other ponies have to use Moochick's magic
梅根和其他小马不得不使用月地精的魔法
to defeat his rainbow of darkness,
来击败他的黑暗彩虹
saving them from a lifetime of enslavement.
让他们免于永生被奴役的命运
All the pink in the world can't disguise the irrefutable fact
世界上所有的粉红色都掩盖不了这无可辩驳的事实
that centaurs and castles and dragons and magic
马人  城堡  龙和魔法
are all standard nerd tropes.
都是书呆子标配
Ergo, My Little Pony is nerdy.
因此  小马宝莉是个书呆动画
Ergo, you, Erica,
因此  你  艾瑞卡
are a nerd.
是个书呆
And how do you know so much about My Little Pony?
你又是怎么知道这么多小马宝莉的
Because I'm...
因为我
a nerd.
是个书呆
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
[POWERING DOWN NOISE]
Let's go...
我们走
nerd.
书呆
You...
你
[STEVE GROANS]
That one stung.
那一下很痛
[GASPS FOR AIR]
Who do you work for?
你为谁工作
For the millionth time, I work at Scoops Ahoy!
说了一百万次了  在海员勺冰淇淋店工作
Scoops Ahoy.
海员勺冰淇淋店
[GROANS]
[STEVE] What the hell?!
什么鬼东西
Look at my outfit!
看看我的衣服
You think I just wear this?!
你们以为我就是穿这个的吗
Think I'm a spy in a sailor's uniform?
以为我是个穿水手服的间谍吗
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
How did you get in?
你怎么进来的
[GASPS] I already told you.
我已经跟你说了
I told you before. [GASPS FOR AIR]
我之前告诉你了
My delivery didn't come,
我的快递没到
and my friends and I,
我跟朋友们以为
we thought that it was left at the loading dock,
外卖被放在装卸区那里了
so we went in the room, and then it turned into an elevator,
所以我们就走进房间  然后房间变成了电梯
and then... and then we dropped and then,
然后...  然后我们不断下坠  然后
next thing we know, I open my eyes,
然后我睁开眼睛
and we're in this...
我们就在这个...
wonderful facility.
美妙的地方了
But I swear to God,
但我向上帝发誓
nobody knows about us, nobody saw us.
没有人知道我们  没人看到我们
You could just let us go, all right?
你就让我们走  好吗
And I'm not gonna tell anybody about this, okay?
我不会把这件事告诉任何人  好吗
Shit happens, life goes on.
人生总有不如意  生活还是要继续
And, uh... ice... ice cream.
还有  冰...  冰淇淋
Ice cream, okay?
冰淇淋  好吗
You guys know what ice cream is. Everybody loves ice cream.
你们知道冰淇淋是什么  人人都喜欢冰淇淋
I don't know if you have Russian ice cream
我不知道你们有没有苏式冰淇淋
or if that's considered gelato.
或者意式冰淇淋
I don't know what's what, but whatever you guys want, seriously.
我有些分不清  但说真的  不管你们想要什么
USS Butterscotch, I mean, you gotta try it.
你们一定要试试奶油糖果战舰
It is out of this world, I'm telling ya!
我跟你讲  那简直是举世无双
[SOLDIERS LAUGHING]
[LAUGHS NERVOUSLY]
I like this guy!
我喜欢这小子
"USS... Butterscotch." [LAUGHS]
"奶油糖果...  战舰"
[SOLDIERS CONTINUE LAUGHING]
[CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHTER STOPS]
Who do you work for?
你为谁做事
Oh, come on. No, no! No, seriously...
拜托  不  不  不  我是认真的...
[SOLDIER GRUNTS]
[SOLDIERS SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[GRUNTING]
Get your hands off me!
放开我
[YELPS, GRUNTS]
Hey...
Steve?
史蒂夫
- [DOOR BUZZER SOUNDS] - Steve? Steve?
史蒂夫  史蒂夫
Steve?
史蒂夫
What did you do to him? What did you do?
你们把他怎么样了  你们做什么了
- [OFFICER GRUNTS] - [ROBIN GROANS]
[WHIMPERS]
[IN RUSSIAN] Put them in the chairs.
把他们绑在椅子上
[SOLDIER SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
[ROBIN] Don't touch me!
别碰我
Steve... [GRUNTS]
史蒂夫
Steve, wake up. Steve?
史蒂夫  醒醒  史蒂夫
[ROBIN GRUNTS, YELPS]
What did you do?!
你们做了什么
[ROBIN GRUNTS]
Don't touch him.
别碰他
[CLICKING TONGUE]
Steve? Steve, can you hear me?
史蒂夫  史蒂夫  能听到我说话吗
[OFFICER, IN ENGLISH] I think your friend need a doctor.
我觉得你朋友需要一个医生
Good thing...
好消息是...
we have the very best.
我们有最棒的医生
[OFFICER LAUGHS]
[SOLDIERS LAUGH]
You are going to regret that, little bitch.
你会后悔的  小婊子
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
[DOOR BUZZER SOUNDS]
Bastards.
混蛋
Let us outta here!
放我们出去
Bastards! Let us out! Let us out!
混蛋  放我们出去  放我们出去
[WATER SPLASHING GENTLY]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[STATIC HISSING]
老年宾果之夜
[MIKE] It can't be good for her to be in there for this long.
她在里面这么久肯定不妙
Mike, you need to relax.
迈克  你需要放轻松
What if she gets brain damage or something?
如果她脑损伤什么的怎么办
Oh, shit. Is that, like, a real thing?
该死  那是真的吗
No, it's not. He made it up.
不是  他瞎编的
Mike doesn't know what he's talking about.
迈克不懂自己在讲什么
- Oh, and you do? - No, I...
-那你懂咯  -不  我...
Yes, from The Hawkins Post.
没错  《霍金斯邮报》的
I... I called a couple days ago about the...
我...  我几天前打电话问过...
- [INDISTINCT MALE VOICE ON PHONE] - Yes, yes, um...
对  是的
I was just...
我只是想...
following up to see if anything else had gone missing,
回来确认一下是不是有其它东西失踪了
or if... Okay.
或者...  好吧
Um, sorry to bother...
抱歉打扰你了...
[DIAL TONE SOUNDING]
[MAX AND MIKE ARGUE INDISTINCTLY IN BACKGROUND]
- [NANCY SIGHS] Who's next? - [JONATHAN] There is no next.
-下一个打给谁  -没有下一个了
Unless you want to start calling random people's homes.
除非你随便挑人家打电话
- It doesn't make sense. - What part of any of this makes sense?
-这说不通  -这一切哪里说得通
There's a pattern, okay? A consistency to their behavior.
这是有模式的  它们的行为肯定有规律
They've been feeding on these chemicals since this started,
它们一开始就吃这种化学物质
and... and, what, they just stop, out of the blue?
然后...怎样  它们突然就不吃了
Maybe they have all the chemicals they need.
也许它们已经吃够了
Maybe they've all turned into those... things.
也许它们已经都变成那些...怪物了
But what about the source?
但源头呢
I mean, did the Mind Flayer just suddenly stop infecting people?
我是说   吸灵魔突然就不感染人类了
And even if the flayed are monsters now, why can't El find them?
即使失灵者现在都是怪物了  为什么一一找不到
Okay, can you guys settle an argument for us?
好吧  你们能帮我们评评理吗
Who do you think should decide El's limits?
你们认为谁应该来决定一一的限度
Mike or Eleven?
迈克还是十一
The way that you frame that is such bullshit.
你这样的描述简直是胡说
It's not bullshit, Mike. This is your whole problem.
这不是胡说  迈克  这就是你的问题所在
And it's also precisely the reason why she dumped your ass.
这也正是她甩掉你的原因
El dumped you?
一一把你甩了
Yeah, because she is conspiring against me.
是的  因为她一直针对我
She's corrupting her.
她在腐化她
No, enlightening her.
不  是启发她
[MAX] The fact is, she's not yours.
事实是  她不属于你
She's her own person, fully capable of making her own decisions.
她属于她自己  完全有能力自己做决定
She's risking her life for no reason.
她无缘无故地用自己的生命冒险
For no reason?
无缘无故
Mike, the flayed are out there doing God knows what.
迈克  失灵者们现在就在外面为所欲为
- Killing, flaying... - Transforming into monsters.
-杀戮  吸灵...  -变身为怪物
And El's not stupid.
而且一一也不是傻子
[NANCY] She knows her abilities better than any of us.
她比我们更了解自己的能力
- Exactly, thank you. - And she is her own person.
-正是  谢谢  -她是个独立的人
- Exactly. - With her own free will.
-正是  -她会按自己的意愿做事
[MAX] Exactly.
正是
El has saved the world twice, and Mike still doesn't trust her.
一一已经两次拯救这世界了  而迈克还是不信任她
You wanna talk about trust, really?
你想来讨论信任吗  真的吗
After you made Eleven spy on us?
你还让十一来偷窥我们
- Wait, what? - Oh, she didn't tell you this?
-等等  什么  -她没告诉你吗
- No. - Your girlfriend used El's powers
-没有  -你女朋友用一一的能力来偷窥我们
- to spy on us. - No, no, no, I did not make her.
不  不  不  不是我让她做的
It was her idea.
是她的主意
And why are we even talking about this, seriously?
说真的  我们为什么要讨论这个
Yeah, who cares?
是啊  谁在乎
- I care. - Yeah.
-我在乎  -没错
I guess girlfriends don't lie, they spy.
看来女朋友都不说谎  她们直接偷窥
We were just joking around.
我们只是在闹着玩
Wouldn't it've been so funny
如果我正好在拉一大坨屎
if I was taking a massive shit or something?
或者别的什么事会不会很好笑
- You weren't. - But what if I was?
-你没在拉  -但如果我有呢
- Then gross! - Seriously, Mike?
-好恶心  -你是认真的吗  迈克
I'm just trying to demonstrate how careless
我只是在说明麦克斯
Max is with Eleven's powers.
有多不小心对待十一的能力
In fact, how careless all of you are.
事实上  你们都很不小心
You're treating her like some kind of machine
你们就像对待一个机器
when she's not a machine,
那样对待她  可她不是机器
and I don't want her to die looking for the flayed
而且我不想她因为寻找失灵者而死
when they've obviously vanished off the face of the Earth.
因为失灵者们显然已经从地球上消失了
So can we please just come up with a new plan
所以能不能拜托大家想个新方案
because I love her and I can't lose her again.
因为我爱她  我不能再失去她了
[DOOR OPENING]
What's going on?
发生什么了
Nothing. Nothing.
没事  没事
Just a family discussion.
集体讨论而已
Oh.
I found him.
我找到他了
Found who?
找到谁了
[MURRAY] He calls it the key, and this key emits a great energy.
他说那叫钥匙  还说钥匙会释放巨大的能量
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MURRAY] It requires much strength, power.
它需要强大的力量  电力
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MURRAY] Those houses, like the one you found,
而那些房屋  比如你们发现的那座
they're located near, uh, transformers.
位于变压器附近
They're stealing from your town's power grid.
正在从你们镇上的电网窃取电力
Why build this key here?
为什么要在这里建造钥匙
Why are they not doing this in their own backyard?
他们怎么不在自己后院造呢
What are they trying to do, blow us to smithereens?
他们想干什么  把我们炸成碎片吗
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[CHUCKLES LIGHTLY]
There were many of these, uh, keys before in Russia,
这样的钥匙  曾经在苏联大量存在
but they turned out wrong.
但最后都无法正常运作
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
They had to come to where the... where the, uh...
他们就得去往  去往
Where the what?
去哪里
- I don't understand what he's saying. - I thought you were fluent.
-我没听懂他说什么  -我以为你俄语很流利呢
Oh, I'm sorry.
抱歉
Are my free translation services not good enough for you?
你们不满意我的免费翻译服务是吗
Because you can just go ahead and file your complaint
你们就是想狠狠控诉我
right up my ass!
也是白搭
What is Smirnoff doing?
司木露干什么呢
- He's showing me. - [SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
他是在告诉我
[MURRAY] Oh, okay.
Uh, he says the straw,
他说吸管
they're using it to penetrate a hole
他们在用吸管打洞
in... a box?
给盒子打洞
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Okay, sorry, sorry.
抱歉抱歉
[MURRAY] The straw represents the key, which emits a great energy.
吸管代表的是钥匙  能够释放庞大的能量
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
They're using this energy...
他们要利用这股能量
to break through a barrier,
冲破阻碍
to open...
来开启
a doorway.
一扇门
A doorway between worlds.
一扇联通不同世界的门
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MURRAY] But it seems this key was only half the equation.
不过似乎钥匙还只是必要条件的一半
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Location... Location was the other half.
选址是条件的另一半
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
Oh, what...
要做什么
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
In Hawkins, this door had been opened once.
在霍金斯  这扇门曾被开启过一次
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
It was still...
它现在还在
healing.
复原中
Jesus Christ.
天啊
So, this door is open now?
所以说  这扇门现在开了
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
He says it is...
他说门
opening.
正在开
- [CREATURE SHRIEKING] - [FLUTTERING SOUND]
[GASPS]
- Where are you going? - To call our children.
-你要干什么  -给孩子们打电话
[GASPS]
[IN RUSSIAN] Can we watch Looney Tunes now?
我们能接着看《乐一通》了吗
Nyet.
不行
[BIG BAND MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
[GRUMBLING]
- Can I help you with something? - Whiskey.
-需要我帮你找点什么吗  -威士忌
- You have whiskey? - No, but I do have vodka.
-你有威士忌没  -没  但伏特加倒是有
[HOPPER SIGHS]
- [HOPPER INHALES SHARPLY] - Oh!
If there's a way to start this key,
有办法开启这把钥匙
there's gotta be a way to stop it, yeah?
就会有办法阻止启用它  对吧
Turn it off?
关了它
- [HOPPER INHALES SHARPLY] - [MURRAY SIGHS]
- Right. - Right?
-没错  -对吧
[IN RUSSIAN] The key, is there a way to turn it off?
那钥匙  有办法关闭吗
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[IN ENGLISH] He says, "Of course he could turn it off. Could...
他说  他当然能把它关掉
Edison not turn off a lamp, could Bell not hang up a phone?"
爱迪生会关不掉电灯吗  贝尔会挂不断电话吗
Cocky bastard. "But..."
自以为是的混蛋  不过
But what?
不过什么
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
But he is now...
不过他现在
"naked".
"光着"
Sorry, "exposed". Compromised.
抱歉  是"暴露了"  有损声誉
Hey, I will get you there.
我带你到那去
I will get you to your key.
我会把你带到你的钥匙那
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[LAUGHS]
You wanna ask him what the hell's so funny about that?
你要不要问问他什么事这么好笑
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
He says he likes your courage.
他说他欣赏你的勇气
You remind him of a...
你在他眼里是
[CLEARS THROAT]
... fat Rambo.
发福版的兰博
兰博  电影《第一滴血》男主角
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MURRAY] But he says that even thin Rambo couldn't get there.
但他说就算是身形健硕的兰博也没法去那里
[ALEXEI SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
This key, it is in an underground fortress
这把钥匙在一座地下堡垒里
designed by the greatest Russian minds,
由苏联的顶尖智囊设计
guarded by their greatest warriors.
有他们的精锐战士守卫
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[MURRAY] Breaking in is...
想要擅闯
impossible.
不可能
Jackpot.
撞大运了
[DUSTIN] Oh-ho-ho!
Do you even know how to drive?
你到底会不会开车
How hard can it be? Max did it.
能有多难  麦克斯都能开
- [DUSTIN] Aw, come on. - You seriously thought
-怎么会这样  -你真以为
- they'd just leave keys in there? - There's gotta be a spare.
-人家会留钥匙在这里  -肯定有把备用的
[ERICA SIGHS]
- [ERICA] Hey, Dustin? - Yeah?
-达斯汀  -怎么了
How big did you say that Demogorgon was?
你说魔王块头有多大来着
Big. Nine feet or so. Why?
超大  差不多两米七高  怎么了
Found 'em.
找到了
Erica?
艾瑞卡
[LOUD ZAPPING]
What the hell is that?!
那是什么玩意
A deadly weapon.
致命武器
Could be useful.
可能会派上用场
- For what? - What do you think?
-什么用场  -你觉得呢
Taking down Commies, saving your friends.
放倒共党  解救你的朋友
Thought you were more realistic than that, nerd.
我还以为你很现实呢  书呆
We don't even know where they are,
我们都不知道他们在哪
and even if we did, there are a million guards up there
就算我们知道在哪  门口也该守了数不清的警卫
with weapons way deadlier than that.
手持比你那更致命的武器
The best thing we can do for them
我们能为他们做的最好的事
is to get out of here and find help.
就是从这离开  寻求帮助
Easy with that.
你悠着点
Our chance of surviving, and theirs, rises substantially.
这样我们和他们存活的几率才大大提高
Just trust me on this. Please?
就信我这一次吧  拜托
[ENGINE POWERING UP]
[ROBIN] Help!
救命
[ROBIN'S VOICE ECHOES]
Help!
救命
- Help! - Hey, would you stop yelling?
-救命  -你能别喊了吗
Steve! Oh, my God!
史蒂夫  我的天啊
[PANTING] Steve...
史蒂夫
Are... Are you okay?
你还好吗
My ears are ringing, and I can't really breathe,
我耳鸣了  呼吸也不顺畅
my eye feels like it's about to pop out of my skull,
眼珠感觉就要从头骨弹出去了
but, you know, apart from that, I'm doing pretty good.
不过除了这些  都挺好的
Well, the good news is that they're calling you a doctor.
好消息是他们要给你叫医生来
[ROBIN CHUCKLES]
Is this his place of work?
这里是办公地点吗
- I love the vibe. - [ROBIN CHUCKLES]
氛围我很喜欢
Charming.
十分宜人
Yeah, tell me about it. So, okay,
可不是嘛
do you see that table over there to your right?
看到你右边的桌子了吗
No, your other right.
不  另一边
- Oh. - Yeah, okay.
-看到了  -好
- And do you see those scissors? - Uh-huh.
-看到那把剪子了吗  -嗯
Yeah, well,
好  试想如果我们
I think that if we move at the same time, we could get over there,
同时挪动  我们就能凑到边上去
and then maybe I could kick the table and knock them into your lap.
我或许能踢动桌子  把剪刀送到你大腿边
- And I could cut the binds. - Yeah, and we could get out of here.
然后我就能把绳索剪开了 对  我们就能逃出这了
- Gotcha. Okay, yeah, we can do that. - Yeah.
-明白了  好的  我们能做到  -对
Those morons. They left scissors in here?
那些蠢货  竟然把剪刀留在这里
- Yeah, morons. [LAUGHS] - Total morons.
-是啊  是够蠢的  -不折不扣的蠢货
- Okay. - Okay, so,
-好了  -好了
on the count of three, we're gonna hop.
我数到三  我们一起跳
- Okay, good, hop on three. I gotcha. - All right.
-好的  数到三就跳  我知道了  -行
One, two, three.
一  二  三
- Okay, that worked. - Okay.
-太好了  刚才那样管用  -好的
- All right. Uh, let's try again. - Right.
-好  咱们再试试  -好
[BOTH] One, two, three.
一  二  三
- Holy shit, this is gonna work! - We're close. Ready?
-我们绝对可以  -越来越近了  准备
Okay, one, two, three.
好  一  二  三
[BOTH GRUNTING]
[BOTH GROANING]
[LAUGHING LIGHTLY]
It's okay, it's okay.
没事  没事
Don't cry. Robin.
罗宾  不要哭
[ROBIN GIGGLES]
Are you laughing?
你在笑吗
[CONTINUES LAUGHING]
- Yeah. - Jesus!
-对  -上帝啊
I'm sorry!
抱歉
I'm so sorry. It's just...
抱歉  只是
I can't believe...
我都不敢信
I'm gonna die in a secret Russian base
我会和"秀发"史蒂夫·哈灵顿
with Steve "The Hair" Harrington.
死在一个苏联秘密基地
- It's just too trippy, man. - We're not gonna die.
-这也太神奇了  -我们不会死的
We're gonna get out of here, okay?
我们会出去的  明白吗
Just... You gotta let me just think for a second.
只要  你让我花点时间想想办法
Do you remember, um, Mrs. Click's sophomore history class?
你记得滴答老师教的高二历史课吗
What?
什么
Mrs. Clickity-Clackity.
滴里搭拉女士
That's what us band dweebs called her.
我们那些乐队怪咖这么叫她
- [SIGHS] - It was first period,
是周二还有周四的第一节课
Tuesdays and Thursdays, so you were always late.
所以你总是迟到
And you always had the same breakfast.
你还总是吃一样的早饭
Bacon, egg, and cheese on a sesame bagel.
芝麻贝果配培根  鸡蛋  奶酪
I sat behind you
那一年每周有两天我就坐在你后面
two days a week for a year.
Mister Funny.
搞笑先生
Mister Cool.
炫酷先生
The King of Hawkins High himself.
霍金斯高中之王本尊
Do you even remember me from that class?
你是不是都不记得我在那节课上
[ROBIN CHUCKLES]
Of course you don't.
你肯定不记得
You were a real asshole, you know that?
你那时就是个混蛋  你知道吗
Yeah, I know.
是  我知道
But it didn't even matter.
但是那不算什么
It didn't matter that you were an ass.
就算你是个混蛋也没什么
I was still...
我那会还是
obsessed with you.
迷恋你
Even though all of us losers pretend to be above it all,
就算我们这些废柴都假装不屑一顾
we still just wanna be popular...
我们还是想受欢迎的
accepted,
想被人认可  普普通通的
normal.
If it makes you feel any better,
如果这样能让你好受些的话
having those things isn't all that great.
有那些称号可不如想象中的那么好
Seriously.
真的
[SIGHS] It just baffles me.
让我很迷惑
Everything that people tell you is important,
人们告诉你很重要的事
everything that people say you should care about, it's all just...
人们告诉你应该关心的事  全都是
[CHUCKLES]
... bullshit.
胡扯
But I guess you gotta mess up to figure things out, right?
不过我看你只有搞砸了之后才能想明白吧
I hope so.
我希望是这样
I feel like my whole life has been...
我觉得我一辈子
one big error.
就是个巨大的错误
[CHUCKLES]
Yep. [LAUGHS]
对
At least it can't get any more messed up than this.
至少不会比现在这样更糟糕了
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
You know, I wish I'd known you in Click's class.
我希望我当时能在滴答女士的课上认识你
- Yeah? - Really, I do.
-是吗  -真的
[ROBIN CHUCKLES]
Maybe you could've helped me pass the class.
说不定你能帮我把那门课弄及格
Maybe instead of being here, I'd be on my way to college right now.
说不定我就不会在这里 而是正在去上大学的路上了
And I would have no idea
我也不会知道
that there were evil Russians beneath our feet,
我们脚下藏着邪恶苏联人了
and I would be happily slinging ice cream with some other schmuck.
我会幸福地 和另外某个蠢蛋一起卖冰淇淋
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Gotta say, though,
我得承认
I liked being your schmuck.
我喜欢当你的蠢蛋朋友
It was fun while it lasted.
至少曾经很开心
It was.
是挺开心的
- [BUZZER SOUNDS] - [DOOR OPENS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHUCKLES]
Where were you two going?
你们想去哪啊
[CLICKING TONGUE]
Try telling the truth this time, yes?
这回试着说实话吧
It will make your visit with Dr. Zharkov less painful.
这会让你和扎科夫博士的会面没那么痛苦
[WINCES]
[CHUCKLES]
Wait a second. Wait. Hold on.
等一下  等等
Okay! Wait, wait, wait! What is that thing?
好  等等  那是什么
It will help you talk.
这会帮你说实话
Did you even clean that thing?!
你是不是都没消过毒
[SCREAMS]
[STATIC HISSING]
[GASPING BREATHS]
[ELEVEN BREATHES RAPIDLY]
[GASPING, PANTING]
What's he doing now?
他现在在干什么
[NANCY] And that's not normal, right?
那样不正常  对吧
Billy staying in his room on the Fourth of July?
比利在国庆节的时候待在他的屋里
No, that's not normal.
那绝对不正常
He wants us to find him.
他想让我们找到他
Yeah, that's what I'm afraid of.
对  我就是担心这点
If we go to Billy, then
如果我们去找比利
the rest of the flayed know where we are.
那其余的失灵者就会知道我们在哪
It's a trap, I agree. We'll be ambushed.
是个陷阱  我同意  我们会被埋伏
We won't be surprised.
我们不会被偷袭
We'll know that they're coming,
我们知道他们会来
and we will kick their flayed butts.
我们会给那些失灵者颜色看看
You mean El will kick their butts.
你是说一一会给他们颜色看看
幸运符  配有棉花糖碎的糖霜燕麦片
[ELEVEN'S VOICE ECHOES] Papa!
爸爸
No.
不
[TERRY] Rainbow. Three to the right, four to the left.
彩虹  右转三下  左转四下
Sunflower. Rainbow.
向日葵  彩虹
- [MIKE] It's too risky. - [NANCY] Yeah, and unnecessary.
-风险太大了  -对  而且没必要
Killing the flayed won't stop the Mind Flayer.
杀掉失灵者不会阻止吸灵魔
We have to find out where it's spreading from.
我们必须找到是从哪里开始扩散的
We have to find the source.
我们要找到根源
[ELEVEN] Billy knows it.
比利知道
Billy's been there.
比利去过那
To the source.
去过源头
- Yeah, but... - It's a trap. I know.
-对  但是  -那是陷阱  我明白
[ELEVEN] We can't go to Billy,
我们不能去找比利
but I think there's another way.
不过我觉得还有一种办法
A way for me to see where he's been.
我能看到他去过的地方
[STATIC HISSING]
El, I know you think you have to do this, but you don't.
一一  你觉得你必须这么做  但其实不是的
It's just, you've only done this before once.
只是  你之前只这么做过一次
And your mom, she loved you,
而且你妈妈  她很爱你
and wanted you to know what happened.
愿意让你知道发生了什么
And Billy's mind is... is sick, diseased.
比利的心思是扭曲  病态的
The Mind Flayer is in him.
吸灵魔在他体内
He can't hurt me.
他伤不了我的
Not in there.
在那是不会的
We don't know that.
我们并不清楚
Mike.
迈克
I need you to trust me.
我要你相信我
Yeah.
好
Just... be careful.
小心点
[SHIVERING BREATHS]
[ELEVEN EXHALES SHARPLY]
[ECHOING] Billy.
比利
Can you hear me?
你听得见吗
I want to see.
我想看看
I want to see what happened.
我想看看发生什么了
[SUSPENSEFUL SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[WHIMPERING]
Something's wrong.
不对劲
[SCREAMS] Stop! No! No! No!
住手  不  不  不
No!
不
[DISTORTED ROARING]
[GASPING]
[BILLY GRUNTING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[DISTORTED SCREAMS]
[SQUAWKING]
[DISTORTED WAILING]
[MIKE, ECHOING] El, are you okay?
一一  你还好吗
Are you okay?
你还好吗
[SIGHS]
[SOFTLY] I'm okay.
我没事
What's going on?
发生什么了
I'm... on a beach.
我在海滩上
[LUCAS] Okay, I may be dense,
我可能有点笨
but the last I checked,
但据我所知
there weren't any beaches in Hawkins.
霍金斯没有海滩
What else do you see?
你还看到了什么
[TIDES CRASHING]
[SEAGULLS SQUAWKING]
[ELEVEN] A woman.
一个女人
She's...
她很漂亮
pretty.
I...
我觉得她在看我
I think she's looking at me.
[ECHOING LAUGHTER]
[WOMAN] Woo!
Yeah!
[WOMAN LAUGHS]
[WOMAN] You did it!
你做到了
There's...
还有一个小男孩
a boy.
Did you see that?
你看到了吗
Yeah, I saw that!
嗯  我看到了
That was at least seven feet.
至少有两米高
[WOMAN] I don't know what it was,
我不知道是怎么回事  但我吓坏了
but it almost gave me a heart attack.
Ten more minutes?
再玩十分钟好吗
- Yeah, okay, ten more minutes. - Okay.
-好  再玩十分钟  -好
But any longer than that, Dad's gonna be mad, okay?
但超过十分钟  爸爸就要生气了  好吗
[BOY] Okay!
好
[BOY PANTING]
Billy?
比利
Watch out for rip currents!
小心激流
I know.
我知道
It's Billy.
那是比利
It's California.
在加利福尼亚
It's a memory.
那是一段回忆
[SEAGULLS SQUAWKING]
[DISTANT RUMBLING]
I think I see it.
我觉得我看到了源头
The source.
[PANTING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING AND CRASHING]
[DIALING ON ROTARY PHONE]
[MURRAY] Two minutes, Jim.
就两分钟  吉姆
It's a secure line,
这是一条安全线路
but any longer than that and they could trace you.
但超过两分钟  他们就会追踪到你
Yeah, I want 'em to trace me.
我想让他们来追踪我
- What? - [HOPPER CLEARS THROAT]
什么
[PHONE RINGING]
费城公共图书馆
Philadelphia Public Library.
Uh...
This is Jim Hopper...
我是吉姆·霍普
uh... police chief, Hawkins.
霍金斯的警察局长
[HOPPER] I got this number from Dr. Sam Owens.
是塞姆·欧文斯博士给我这个号码的
What is your identification code?
你的身份码是什么
Identification code?
身份码
You don't know it?
你不知道吗
You must be joking.
你在开玩笑吧
Oh, no, no, I got it, I got it.
不  不  我找到了  找到了
[CHUCKLES] I got it.
我知道
You wrote it down and kept it in your wallet?
你居然把它写下来  放在钱包里
"Antique Chariot". Listen.
古董战车  听着
[HOPPER] Um, tell Owens that the Russkies are opening the gate.
告诉欧文斯  苏联人要打开入口了
Now, he'll know what that means.
他会明白的
Not about the Russkies, but about the gate.
我不是指苏联人 而是指入口
Tell him that there's an entrance at Starcourt Mall.
告诉他  星庭商场里有一个入口
I know how to get in,
我知道怎么进去
but I need backup, a lot of backup.
但我需要大量支援
Have him call me back here at 618-625-8313.
让他给我回电6186258313
Your message will be relayed.
你的信息将被传达
- So, now what? - Now, we, uh...
-现在怎么办  -我们就等着
we wait.
You compromised me, Jim.
你让我陷入危险了  吉姆
You do realize that, don't you? I'm gonna have to relocate.
你知道的  对吗  我得转移了
- How long do we wait? - As long as it takes.
-要等多久  -等他打来为止
How can you just sit there being calm?
你怎么能这么冷静地坐着
I am not calm!
我不冷静
Our kids are in danger!
我们的孩子有危险
You said they were at the festival!
你说他们在参加节日庆典
Which is, like, ten minutes from the gate!
那地方离入口就只有十分钟路程
[SCOFFS]
What are you doing? Joyce?
你要干什么  乔伊
What are you doing?
你要干什么
[PHONE RINGS]
费城公共图书馆
Philadelphia Public Library.
Yes, hello.
你好
Uh, this is, uh, Antique Chariot's partner...
我是古董战车的搭档
Wheelbarrow.
独轮车
I don't think Antique Chariot
古董战车没有
properly conveyed the urgency of our situation.
准确地传达情况的紧急
What are you doing?
你在干什么
Can't just sit around and wait for a call.
我不能坐着干等电话
- Ma'am, I'm gonna need you to stay calm. - No.
-女士  你要保持冷静  -不
Don't you dare patronize me!
别以高人一等的态度对待我
I don't know who you are,
我不知道你是谁
if you're some glorified secretary or what,
不管你是什么光荣秘书
but if you don't wanna lose your job,
你要是不想丢饭碗  就按我说的做
here's what's gonna happen.
When I hang up,
我挂电话后
you're gonna get up off your ass,
你马上起身
and you're gonna go find Owens and tell him what's going on.
去找欧文斯  告诉他发生了什么
We don't have time to talk about it and neither does he.
我们没时间讨论  他也一样
He's gotta get to Hawkins,
他得来霍金斯
and he's gotta bring his men right now!
带上他的人马立刻过来
Do you understand me?
你听明白了吗
Yes, yes, ma'am.
是的  明白了  女士
Thank you. And good day.
谢谢  再见
It's been exactly one minute, Joyce.
刚好一分钟  乔伊
That's one minute too long.
一分钟太久了
- Alexei. - [GASPS]
阿列克西
[IN RUSSIAN] What's going on?
怎么了
We gotta go. Vroom, vroom.
我们得走了  快
Back to Hawkins. Come on.
回去霍金斯  快
[JOYCE] Come on.
快走
Honestly, I don't really feel anything.
老实说  我没什么感觉
Do you?
你呢
I mean, I... I feel fine.
我感觉还好
- I feel normal. - Yeah, I feel... I feel fine.
-我感觉正常  -我感觉还好
I kinda feel good.
我感觉不错
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
- Wanna know a secret? - What?
-想知道一个秘密吗  -什么
I like it, too!
我也喜欢这种感觉
[BOTH LAUGH]
- I feel good. - Morons. They messed up the drug.
-我感觉很好  -蠢货  他们打错药了吧
They messed it up!
他们搞砸了
- Morons. Hey, morons! - Morons!
-蠢货  蠢货  -蠢货
- Moron! Mor... - Hey!
蠢货  蠢货
Whoa-oh!
Oh, no. There's definitely something wrong with us.
我们肯定有不对劲
- Something's wrong. - [DOOR BUZZER SOUNDS]
不对劲
[ROBIN CHUCKLES]
Would now be a good time to tell you that I don't like doctors?
我现在能说我不喜欢医生吗
Let's try this again, yes?
我们再来一次  好吗
[MURMURS]
Who do you work for?
你们为谁工作
Scoops. [CHUCKLES]
勺子
Scoops Ahoy.
海员勺
[GIGGLES]
How did you find us?
你是怎么找到我们的
Totally by accident. [CHUCKLES]
完全是个意外
[STEVE CHUCKLES]
[IN RUSSIAN] More lies.
继续耍我们
What is that shiny little toy?
-那闪亮的小玩意是什么  -医生你要用它干什么
[ROBIN] Where you going with that, doc?
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey. Wait! No! Wait! Wait!
等等  不要  等等  等等
- Whoa! - There was a code! We heard a code!
密码  密码  我们听到一条密码
Code.
密文
What code?
什么样的密文
"The week is long.
"这周很长
The silver cat feeds when blue meets yellow in the west."
当蓝在西边遇到黄  银猫进食"
Blah, blah, blah.
什么  什么的
You broadcast that stupid spy shit all over town,
你在镇上满世界地播报这该死的间谍消息
and we picked it up on our Cerebro,
被我们的脑波增幅器截获了
and we cracked it in a day.
然后我们一天就把它破译了
A day!
就一天
You think you're so smart,
你自以为很聪明
but a couple of kids who scoop ice cream for a living
但几个冰淇淋店打工的孩子
cracked your code in a day, and now, people know you're here.
一天之内就破译了你的密文 现在大家都知道你在这里
Who knows we are here, little bitch?
还有谁知道我们在这里  小混蛋
Uh, well, Dustin knows.
达斯汀也知道
Hey, Steve?
史蒂夫
- Yeah, Dustin Henderson, he knows. - Steve!
-达斯汀·亨德森  他也知道  -史蒂夫
- [STEVE LAUGHS] - Dustin Henderson.
达斯汀·亨德森
It is your small, curly-haired friend?
是你那个卷毛小朋友吗
Oh, curly-haired. Great hair. Small. Kind of like a 'fro. Yeah.
卷发  漂亮的卷发  小个子  有点像女孩
Where is he?
他在哪里
He's long gone, you big asshole.
他早就跑了  你这个大混蛋
And he's probably calling Hopper,
他可能已经在给霍普打电话了
and Hopper's calling the US cavalry. [LAUGHS]
霍普再打给美国装甲部队
They're gonna come in here, commando-style, guns a-blazin',
他们会来这里突击你们  火力全开
and kick your sorry asses back to Russia.
把你们这帮可怜虫打回俄罗斯老家
You're gonna be two pieces of toast.
你会被打成两半
[SNICKERS]
Is that so?
是这样吗
Yeah.
当然了
[BOTH LAUGH]
[LAUGHS]
[ALARM BLARING]
[SOLDIERS YELLING IN RUSSIAN]
[SPEAKING RUSSIAN]
[OFFICER GRUNTS A COMMAND]
- [SIZZLING] - [ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
[INTENSE SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMING]
Hey! Henderson!
亨德森
That's crazy, I was just talking about you.
太疯狂了  我刚刚还讲到你
- Oh, my God! - Get ready to run.
-天哪  -准备逃走
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[WIND HOWLING]
[OMINOUS SYNTH MUSIC PLAYING]
[MAN] Hey! Billy, stop!
比利  住手
What the hell is wrong with you? What did we talk about, huh?
你到底怎么了  我们之前是怎么说的
You gotta slide!
你得滑垒
- [STAMMERING] I know. - Wait.
-我知道  -等等
- Afraid you're gonna get hurt, is that it? - No.
-你怕会受伤  对吗  -不是
[MAN] Well, what then? What?
那是为什么  到底为什么
What did I raise, a pussy for a son?
我养了个软蛋儿子吗
- Leave me alone! - Hey!
别管我
[MAN] That's right, run! Like you always do!
好啊  逃吧  你只会逃走
[LIGHTNING CRACKLING]
[THUNDERCLAP]
[MAN] Where were you last night? Where were you?
昨晚你去哪儿了  你在哪里
- [WOMAN] I told you, I was with Wendy. - [MAN] Stop lying to me!
-我说了我和温迪在一起  -别再骗我了
- [WOMAN] I'm not lying to you! - You saw him again, didn't you?
-我没有骗你  -你又去见他了  是不是
- Didn't you?! - Get away from me!
-是不是  -离我远点
- I said, get away! - You... You whore!
-我叫你滚开  -你  你这个婊子
- Stop it! - Bitch!
-住手  -荡妇
- Don't hurt her! - No!
-别伤害她  -不
- Don't hurt her! - [WOMAN] You bastard!
-别伤害她  -你这个禽兽
[MAN GRUNTS]
[YOUNG BILLY] Mom!
妈妈
[YOUNG BILLY] I don't understand. Why not?
我不明白  为什么不行呢
Please, Mom, don't do this.
求你了  妈妈  别这样
Please come home.
求你回家吧
No. How long? How long?!
不  要过多久  要过多久
[SOBBING] I miss you.
我很想你
[TEEN BILLY] Get back here!
你给我回来
[GRUNTING]
Get up! What, are you scared to fight me?
起来啊  怎么了  你不敢和我打吗
You scared?
你怕了吗
Get up and fight me, pussy! Pussy!
起来和我打  软蛋  你这个软蛋
[MAN] Billy, come over here, I want you to meet someone.
比利  过来  我要你见个人
This is your new sister. Her name's Maxine.
这是你的新妹妹  她叫麦克辛
Max.
叫我麦克斯
- Shake her hand. - [BILLY] Who's there?
-和她握个手  -谁在那儿
[MAN] I said, shake her hand.
-我说了和她握手  -我说了谁在那里
[BILLY] I said, who's there?! [SCREAMS]
[BILLY SCREAMS]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[LIGHTNING CRACKLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING AND BOOMING]
I think I found it.
我想我找到了
[ELEVEN PANTING]
The source.
那个源头
Where, El? Where are you?
在哪里  一一  你在哪
Brimborn...
布里伯恩
Steelworks.
炼钢厂
Here. Okay, uh, steelworks, steelworks...
好吧  炼钢厂  炼钢厂
Uh...
Here, steel.
在这  钢铁
Uh...
钢铁分销与仓储
布里伯恩  炼钢厂
樱桃橡树街6522号
[JONATHAN] Found it. 6522 Cherry Oak Drive.
找到了  在樱桃橡树街6522号
- That's close. - El, El, we found it. Get out of there.
离这儿很近 一一 一一 我们找到了  快离开那里
[MIKE] Get out.
快离开
[ECHOING SCREAM]
[DISTORTED SCREAM]
[GASPS]
[PANTING]
Mike?
迈克
[WHIMPERS]
Mike!
迈克
[ECHOING] Mike!
[BILLY, WITH DEEP VOICE] He can't hear you.
他听不到你
[GASPS]
You shouldn't have looked for me.
你不应该来找我的
Because now I see you.
因为现在我看见你了
Now we can all see you.
所以我们都能看见你了
[DRAMATIC CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
You...
是你
let us in.
放我们进来的
[CREATURE ROARING]
And now...
那现在
you are going to have to let us stay.
你也得让我们留下来
[BOY LAUGHING]
David, where you going?
戴维  你去哪儿
David?
戴维
[EXCITED CHEERING]
Adam!
亚当
You're gonna miss it!
你会错过表演的
Adam!
亚当
[FIRECRACKERS CRACKLING]
Don't you see?
你还不明白吗
All this time,
一直以来
we've been building it.
我们都在建造它
- [SOBBING] - We've been building it...
我们建造它
for you.
是为了你
All that work,
所以的付出
all that pain...
所有的痛苦
all of it... for you.
都是  为了你
- [ELEVEN SOBBING] - And now it's time.
现在是时候
Time to end it.
终结一切了
And we are going to end you.
我们会先终结你
And when you are gone,
等你不在了
we are going to end your friends.
我们再去终结你的朋友们
- No! - And then we are going to end...
-不要  -最后  我们会终结
everyone.
所有人
[SCREAMING] Get away!
走开
No!
不要
El, you're okay. It's... It's okay.
一一  你没事了  没事了
El.
一一
[SOBBING]
[LOW FREQUENCY RUMBLING]
[CREATURE SHRIEKING]
[CHOKING NOISES]
[CREATURE SNARLS]
[CREATURE LOWING]
[CHOKING NOISES]
[SQUELCHING NOISES]
[CREATURE SHRIEKING]
[CREATURE SNARLS]
[MAN GRUNTS]
[SQUELCHING NOISES]
[POUNDING AND RATTLING GATE]
[CREATURE SHRIEKS]
[ROARING]
[DRAMATIC ORCHESTRAL AND CHORAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
☆谢谢观赏☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
[MONKEY SCREECHES]